<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Magic Items</name>
		<update version="0.1.1">
			<file name="Magicitems.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Julitutu/Steinhardt-s-Guide-to-the-Eldritch-Hunt/refs/heads/main/Setting/Magicitems.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

    <element name="Bag of Cannonballs" type="Magic Item" source="Steinhardt's Guide to the Eldritch Hunt" id="ID_LT_SGEH_BAG_OF_CANNONBALLS">
        <description>
            <p>You can store up to 100 cannonballs in this bag. The bag weighs 3 pounds, no matter how many cannonballs are stored. You can store or take out up to 3 cannonballs at a time once on each of your turns with no actions required.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="3">3 lb.</set>
            <set name="stash" lb="0" count="100" weightless="true">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Damascena" type="Magic Item" source="Steinhardt's Guide to the Eldritch Hunt" id="ID_LT_SGEH_DAMASCENA">
        <description>
            <p>This basic technology invented by the Scions sacrifices lead bullets to generate powerful azure flames that scorch the abhorrent. This device is an effort to replicate the magical ability possessed by a select few.</p>
            <p>As an action, you can cause the damascena to project blue flames in a 15-foot cone in front of you. Each creature in the cone must make a Dexterity saving throw (DC 11 + your proficiency bonus), taking 4d4 fire damage + a number of d4s equal to your proficiency bonus on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. Each use of the damascena consumes 5 lead bullets.</p>
            <p><i>“Immolation is a sign of purity, and in death they shall be cleansed.”</i></p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="White Fungic Tea" type="Magic Item" source="Steinhardt's Guide to the Eldritch Hunt" id="ID_LT_SGEH_FUNGIC_TEA_WHITE">
        <description>
        <p>The aroma and appearance of this tea are undeniably repulsive, with seemingly still-living organisms squirming within it. However, for those who can stomach it, the tea offers impressive soothing properties.</p>
        <p>Known for temporarily alleviating the effects of madness, the darker the tea, the more potent and challenging to brew. Once ingested, the afflicted individual is relieved of One short-term madness for 1 hour or until the madness ends, whichever is shorter. However, upon swallowing the tea, you must make a DC 12 Constitution saving throw. On a failure, you can’t stomach the appalling taste, regurgitate the tea, and don’t gain the benefits.</p>
        <p>The tea is made in kettles that can pour up to 2d4 cups.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="type">Potion</set>
            <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Yellow Fungic Tea" type="Magic Item" source="Steinhardt's Guide to the Eldritch Hunt" id="ID_LT_SGEH_FUNGIC_TEA_YELLOW">
        <description>
        <p>The aroma and appearance of this tea are undeniably repulsive, with seemingly still-living organisms squirming within it. However, for those who can stomach it, the tea offers impressive soothing properties.</p>
        <p>Known for temporarily alleviating the effects of madness, the darker the tea, the more potent and challenging to brew. Once ingested, the afflicted individual is relieved of All short-term and one long-term madness for 1 hour or until the madness ends, whichever is shorter. However, upon swallowing the tea, you must make a DC 14 Constitution saving throw. On a failure, you can’t stomach the appalling taste, regurgitate the tea, and don’t gain the benefits.</p>
        <p>The tea is made in kettles that can pour up to 2d4 cups.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="type">Potion</set>
            <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Blue Fungic Tea" type="Magic Item" source="Steinhardt's Guide to the Eldritch Hunt" id="ID_LT_SGEH_FUNGIC_TEA_BLUE">
        <description>
        <p>The aroma and appearance of this tea are undeniably repulsive, with seemingly still-living organisms squirming within it. However, for those who can stomach it, the tea offers impressive soothing properties.</p>
        <p>Known for temporarily alleviating the effects of madness, the darker the tea, the more potent and challenging to brew. Once ingested, the afflicted individual is relieved of All short-term and long-term madness for 1 hour or until the madness ends, whichever is shorter. However, upon swallowing the tea, you must make a DC 16 Constitution saving throw. On a failure, you can’t stomach the appalling taste, regurgitate the tea, and don’t gain the benefits.</p>
        <p>The tea is made in kettles that can pour up to 2d4 cups.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="type">Potion</set>
            <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Black Fungic Tea" type="Magic Item" source="Steinhardt's Guide to the Eldritch Hunt" id="ID_LT_SGEH_FUNGIC_TEA_BLACK">
        <description>
        <p>The aroma and appearance of this tea are undeniably repulsive, with seemingly still-living organisms squirming within it. However, for those who can stomach it, the tea offers impressive soothing properties.</p>
        <p>Known for temporarily alleviating the effects of madness, the darker the tea, the more potent and challenging to brew. Once ingested, the afflicted individual is relieved of All short-term and long-term; one indefinite madness for 1 hour or until the madness ends, whichever is shorter. However, upon swallowing the tea, you must make a DC 18 Constitution saving throw. On a failure, you can’t stomach the appalling taste, regurgitate the tea, and don’t gain the benefits.</p>
        <p>The tea is made in kettles that can pour up to 2d4 cups.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="type">Potion</set>
            <set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
        </setters>
    </element>


    <element name="Hand of Glory" type="Magic Item" source="Steinhardt's Guide to the Eldritch Hunt" id="ID_LT_SGEH_HAND_OF_GLORY">
        <description>
            <p>A hand of glory is crafted from the hand of a hanged scourgeborne after it was covered in corpse wax and left to ferment in a casket.</p>
            <p>While holding the hand of glory, you can attune to one additional magical item. This magical item can only be a ring, and must be worn on the hand of glory.</p>
            <p>While holding the hand, you can use an action to set a digit of the hand ablaze and cast the invisibility spell on yourself. While a finger is ablaze, it casts bright light in a 10-foot radius that is only visible to the wearer of the hand. The spell ends early if the flame is extinguished by the wearer (no action required). In addition, while a finger is ablaze, you can cast the knock spell at will on objects within the radius of the light. The hand has 5 digits and regenerates 1 burnt digit daily at dusk.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Holy Tonic" type="Magic Item" source="Steinhardt's Guide to the Eldritch Hunt" id="ID_LT_SGEH_HOLY_TONIC">
        <description>
            <p>The mostly-clear tonic in this vial is slightly milky and sparkles when light shines through. It was originally created by a secretive branch of the Radiant Church. When you drink this tonic, you regain 4d4 + 4 hit points and are cured of all diseases you currently suffer from.</p>
            <p><b><i>Side Effects</i></b></p>
            <p>Depending on the lore your game implements, the holy tonic can have one or more of the following side effects. These effects are hidden from player characters and no magic can reveal them.</p>
            <ul>
                <li>If you fall unconscious within 1d12 minutes after drinking the holy tonic, you must succeed a DC 12 Wisdom saving throw or gain a long-term madness when you regain consciousness.</li>
                <li>1 hour after you drink the holy tonic, you hear whispering voices urging you toward violence and chaos. You must succeed on a DC 10 Wisdom saving throw or have disadvantage on any Persuasion checks for the next 1d4 hours. Additionally, for the duration, you are compelled to act on aggressive impulses as determined by the GM.</li>
                <li>24 hours after you drink the holy tonic, you must succeed on a DC 10 Wisdom saving throw or gain a short-term madness.</li>
                <li>24 hours after you drink the holy tonic, you must succeed on a DC 11 Wisdom saving throw or crave more holy tonic. For the next 1d4 hours, you desperately search for a holy tonic and drink the first one you find. If you do not drink one within this time, you gain 1 level of exhaustion and the craving goes away.</li>
                <li>Each subsequent holy tonic you drink in a 7-day period increases the DCs for the saving throws you must make by 1. Each three holy tonics you drink in a 7-day period increases any exhaustion levels the tonic causes by 1.</li>
                <li>If you fail five Wisdom saving throws caused by a holy tonic within a 7-day period, a curse fully takes hold. You undergo a horrifying transformation into a monstrous beast, losing control of your actions and permanently becoming a beast or monstrosity of the GM’s choice under their control.</li>
            </ul>
            <div class="sidebar">
            <p class="flavor">GM Note: Alternatively the holy tonic can restore 6d4+6 or 8d4+8 hit points.</p></div>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Potions</set>
            <set name="type">Potion</set>
            <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
            <set name="stackable">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Sanctified Cannon" type="Magic Item" source="Steinhardt's Guide to the Eldritch Hunt" id="ID_LT_SGEH_SANCTIFIED_CANNON">
		<description>
			<p><i>“Heed my blessing brothers! Fire the cannons and let the sanctified lead rip apart the flesh of beasts. In death they shall know peace!” —Brother Ardeal</i></p>
			<p><b><i>Charged Shot.</i></b> Once on each of your turns you can replace one of your cannon attacks with a charged shot. Instead of a regular attack, you let loose a ball of destruction and death. Each creature in a 120-foot-long, 5-foot-wide line in front of you must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw against your Firearm save DC or take 3d12 bludgeoning damage and be knocked prone. You can use this property only if you haven’t moved during this turn, and after you use the property, your speed is 0 until the end of the current turn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="type" addition="cannon">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_LT_SGEH_WEAPON_CANNON</set>
			<set name="name-format">Sanctified {{parent}}</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Big Bertha" type="Magic Item" source="Steinhardt's Guide to the Eldritch Hunt" id="ID_LT_SGEH_BIG_BERTHA">
		<description>
			<p>Why bother cutting beasts when you can just blow them to smithereens.</p>
			<p>This moongold inlaid cannon deals an extra 1d4 damage to any non-humanoid creatures it hits. Moongold acts as a guiding light in the darknes; creatures holding or wearing moongold have advantage on saving throws against being frightened and madness.</p>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this weapon.</p>
      <p>As a bonus action, you can rotate the dials on the cannon to infuse your loaded ammo with violent powers. Your next attack deals magical damage and you can choose one of the following effects.</p>
			<ul>
        <li><strong><em>Forceful Infusion.</em></strong> On a hit, the target takes an extra 1d6 bludgeoning damage and must succeed on a Strength saving throw or be pushed 15 feet away and knocked prone. Alternatively, if you are standing on a solid surface and instead fire the cannon directly at your feet, the explosion pushes you into the air and you land in a square of your choice within 30 feet of the explosion’s origin.</li>
        <li><strong><em>Incendiary Infusion.</em></strong> On a hit, the target takes an extra 3d4 fire damage.</li>
        <li><strong><em>Unstable Infusion.</em></strong> On a hit, the target takes an extra 1d8 cold damage and the terrain in a 10-foot radius centered on the target is covered in arcane mist, becoming difficult terrain for the next minute.</li>
      </ul>
    </description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="type" addition="cannon">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_LT_SGEH_WEAPON_CANNON</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
            <set name="name-format">Big Bertha</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
    
    <!-- Moongold weapons -->
    <element name="Moongold Coating" type="Magic Item" source="Steinhardt's Guide to the Eldritch Hunt" id="ID_LT_SGEH_MAGIC_ITEM_MOONGOLD_COATING">
		<description>
			<p>Some monsters that have immunity or resistance to nonmagical or magical weapons are susceptible to moongilded weapons, so cautious adventurers invest extra coin to plate their weapons, magical or not, with moongold.</p>
			<p class="indent">Moongold gives a 1d4 bonus to damage rolls against nonhumanoid creatures. Moongold acts as a guiding light in the darkness; creatures holding or wearing moongold have advantage on saving throws against being frightened and madness.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can moongild a single weapon or ten pieces of ammunition for 1000 gp. This cost represents not only the price of the moongold, but the time and expertise needed to add moongold to the weapon without making it less effective. Moongold loses its effectiveness over time; if a moongilded weapon has not been recoated in moongold after 3 months, the coating falls off, ending its effects. Recoating a weapon before it loses its moongilding costs 500 gp and refreshes the duration of the moongold.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">1000</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Common</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_RANGED||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_RANGED</set>
			<set name="name-format">Moongold {{parent}}</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
</elements>
